<openassessment allow_file_upload="False" allow_latex="True" submission_due="2029-01-01T00:00:00+00:00" submission_start="2001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00">
  <title>Paper Review Assessment</title>
    <assessments>
      <assessment name="peer-assessment" must_grade="5" must_be_graded_by="3" start="2015-02-05T12:00:00+00:00" due="2015-02-19T12:00:00+00:00"/>
    </assessments>
    <rubric>
      <prompt>Please pick one of the papers above, or if you know of a good paper that fits into this week's topic, pick that one.

Look through the paper you chose, and try to understand what is happening.

OK, begin forming your report: start by copying the paper title and the URL.
THIS IS IMPORTANT! (Your report will be read by your colleagues, and they will need this information.)

First, try to tell: what is the main thing that happens in the paper. What do the authors do?

Next, write in a single paragraph: which concepts that you learned this week appear in the paper?
Where do they appear?

Now in a new paragraph answer what new things you learned from the paper, compared to what you learned from our course?
It's OK if you don't understand some (or even most) details, but try to find and formulate at least something new that you have learned.
Point out to the places in text or to figures, which are the most valuable.

Finally tell: What do you think are the strong sides of the paper?
What are the weak sides? Do you see something that you think could be improved?
Do you have some questions that the authors do not answer?
Explain why you think that way.</prompt>
      <criterion feedback="optional">
        <name>Ideas</name>
        <label>Helpfulness</label>
        <prompt>Did reading the report help you to understand what the paper is about?
(Here and later if you were reviewing the same paper, try to imagine that you didn't read it before)</prompt>
        <option points="1">
          <name>0</name>
          <label>No</label>
          <explanation>I couldn't relate the report and the paper.</explanation>
        </option>
        <option points="3">
          <name>1</name>
          <label>Partially</label>
          <explanation>I could understand the overall direction of the paper, but not the main idea.</explanation>
        </option>
        <option points="5">
          <name>2</name>
          <label>Yes</label>
          <explanation>After reading the report I fully knew what to expect from the paper.</explanation>
        </option>
      </criterion>
      <criterion feedback="optional">
        <name>0</name>
        <label>Insight</label>
        <prompt>Did you learn something from the report itself (before you read the paper)</prompt>
        <option points="1">
          <name>1</name>
          <label>Low</label>
          <explanation>The review has no additional information</explanation>
        </option>
        <option points="3">
          <name>0</name>
          <label>Average</label>
          <explanation>The review nicely relates the paper to what we learned.</explanation>
        </option>
        <option points="5">
          <name>2</name>
          <label>High</label>
          <explanation>I learned from the report something I didn't see neither in the paper nor in the course.</explanation>
        </option>
      </criterion>
      <criterion feedback="optional">
        <name>1</name>
        <label>Paper Evaluation</label>
        <prompt>Do you find the evaluation of the strengths and weaknesses of the paper shown in the report convincing?</prompt>
        <option points="1">
          <name>0</name>
          <label>Weak</label>
          <explanation>I could not find the strengths and weaknesses of the paper that were pointed out in the report.
</explanation>
        </option>
        <option points="3">
          <name>1</name>
          <label>Competent</label>
          <explanation>I agree with the evaluation of the strengths and weaknesses, but the argumentation presented was not completely clear.</explanation>
        </option>
        <option points="5">
          <name>2</name>
          <label>Excellent</label>
          <explanation>I think the author of the report really understand the paper well, and knows its ins and outs.</explanation>
        </option>
      </criterion>
      <feedbackprompt>(Optional) What aspects of this report stood out to you? What did it do well? How could it improve?
</feedbackprompt>
      <feedback_default_text>This report was...
</feedback_default_text>
    </rubric>
  </openassessment>
